(240) 566-2353

neerajdesai@outlook.com

System Engineer

Productive System Engineer acknowledged for talents in precisely conceptualizing and directing the development and countinous refinement of advance technology solutions to meet clients' needs

Performance driven, highly accomplished, and a system and network engineer, with 2+ years of experience in application deployment and network design. Well versed in Agile development practices and large scale software configuration management.

IMMEDIATE VALUE OFFERED

- ☑ Thorough understanding of SDLC, test life cycle and defect life cycle, exhibit excellence in analyzing test data, preparing software test cases
- ☑ **Possess expertise** in Business Process Understanding, Requirement Understanding, ✓ Possess expertise in Business Process Understanding, Requirement Understanding, Application Development, Procedure Development, and Project Documentation
 ✓ Evaluate stated requirements and expectations in terms of technical feasibility,
- cost, organizational priorities, and outcomes
- ☑ Facilitating creative solutions using available tools and technologies, including application debugging analysis and resolution

Multi Level Project Management

- SDLC Methodologies
- Configuration and Automation Management
- Network Routing Protocols
- Linux Operating System PowerShell Scripting
- IIRA (issue tracking)

PROFESSIONAL WORK HISTORY

NETWORK ENGINEER

Lockheed Martin (SSC)- Gaithersburg, MD

FEBRUARY 2016 - PRESENT

Develop complex network solution to enhance existing government's nuclear systems and meet all requirements. Manage network design in development environments and work closely with vendors to create solutions for our needs.

- Analyze government requirements to create action plans and help develop RFP document
- **Implemented** the best solution by researching difference protocols ISIS, SPB, and OSPF
- Employed best practices and deployment methodologies to ensure quality of custom protocol created in C++
- Created and analyzed network simulations of difference route convergence after nodes go down
- Demonstrated expertise in
- networking and new technologies
- **Tools:** Qualnet (network simulation), wireshark, ostinato (network traffic generator), TortoiseSVN (subversion)
- **Received recognition** for outstanding accomplishments and work ethic

SEPTEMBER 2015 - FEBRUARY 2016

SYSTEM ENGINEER

Lockheed Martin (IS&GS)- Washington, D.C.

Demonstrated technology leadership and charged with the responsibilities to analyze, troubleshoot, and address technical issues as well as develop tools and solutions for process improvements. Managed installation of code patches in production and development environments. Facilitated tests to ensure proper functioning of systems in various environments.

- Managed configuration management and deployment from test environments to production environments
- Created software baseline, builds, and releases, in parallel to documenting changes and writing deployment instructions
- **Spearheaded efforts** to automating continuous integration for developer environments. Determined hardware upgrades to increase productivity and improve the automation
- Streamlined and structured configuration which increased efficiency by 75%
- **Automating** continuous integration saved developer's time by 50%
- Tools: SharePoint Servers, PowerShell, JIRA, Visual Studio

SUMMER INTERNSHIP

Verizon Enterprise Solution - Ashburn, VA

JUNE 2013 - AUGUST 2013

• Developed a system to automate procurement documents by coding macros in Excel to increase efficiency by 50%

NETWORK SPECIALIST

SYP Group, LLC- Ellicott City, MD

MAY 2011 - JANUARY 2012

• Redesigned network infrastructure and configured related hardware (network routers, hubs, firewalls, CAT-5 wiring, etc)

EDUCATION

University of Maryland, Baltimore County

AUGUST 2015

Bachelors of Science, Computer Engineering (ABET Accredited)

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY